Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Dallas Office Records, 1982-1991 and undated RL.11134
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Dallas Office records
1982-1991 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11134
0.4 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Dallas Office records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Collection Overview
Collection includes research and planning reports, clippings and other printed materials, and artifacts. Companies represented include Burger King, Kraft, and Ford. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising agencies -- Texas; Advertising agencies -- United States; J. Walter Thompson Company
- General Files, 1982-1991 and undated; 1
  - All About Radio, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Burger King--Clippings, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Burger King Post Analysis Report, 1986 (Box 1)
  - David Ogilvy interview--Kenneth Jacobsen, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Ford sticker: Mama don't let your babies grow up to drive Chevies, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Getting Fired from JWT Syndication--Andrew Feinberg, circa 1983 (Box 1)
  - Hat--U.S. Dept of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), undated (Box 1)
  - In defense of Mass Media, 1989 (Box 1)
  - JWT's Problems Continue After Acquisition by WPP--Joanne Lipman, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Kraft Cracker Barrel (AdWeek, Art Direction), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Primetime Television Schedule 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Restructuring at JWT to Tighten Spot-Buying Process (TV-Radio Age), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Scarf: Fascinatin' Syndication, undated (Box 1)
  - Staff photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - The Strange Case of Marie Luisi--Bernice Kanner, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Today's Television Environment, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Visor: JWT Showdown, 1991 (Box 1)